Guide to the Jascha Heifetz Collection ARS.0046
Archive of Recorded Sound
- 10" Sound Discs, 78 rpm discs
  - Commercially Released Recordings, 78 rpm discs
    - Box 2: Edison/His Master's Voice/(Disque pour) Gramophone/Miscellaneous Labels, 78 rpm discs
      Tangos; Waltzes; Popular instrumental music -- England; Ohman, Phil; Orquesta Tipica Francisco Canaro; Arden, Victor; Corrêa, Ruth Valladares; Magyary Imre Cigányzenekara; Ottetto Brasil; Bonnie Blue-Eyes; Odeon-Orchester; Miranda, Aurora; Orchestre symphonique du Gramophone; Efendi, Kanuni Artaki; Sandor, Arpad; Effendi, Zournadji Emin
      - Varsovienne, [1925?]; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 25)
        Varsovienne: for violin solo, violin duet, viola solo, 'cello solo and string quartet
        Edison Record: 9883R, 9884L; 9883-A-2-4, 9884-E-1-B (matrix)
        Special record for Mr. Henry Ford
      - Bihari, János, 1764-1827. Mikor a penze elfogyott -- Csermák, Antal György, 1774?-1822. Disz palotás, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 33)
        Performed by Magyary Imre Cigányzenekara
        His Master's Voice: Am 3120; BE2655-1[triangle], BE2656-1[triangle] (matrix); 70-1564-G, 70-1565-G (additional matrix nos.)
      - Soultanigiah Taxim -- Hidjaz Charki, Adali, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 34)
        Performed by Kanoni Artaki Effendi [i.e. Kanuni Artaki Efendi] [side A], Réhbéri Musiki Héyéti [side B]
        His Master's Voice: AX. 496; BF1413-1[triangle], BF1328-1[triangle] (matrix); 7-219352, 7-210591 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Rast Taxim -- Kadifé Charkissi, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 35)
        Rast Taxim: instrumental solo Performed by Zournadji Emin Effendi
        Kadifé Charkissi: male song Performed by Mahmoud Bey
        His Master's Voice: AX. 503; BF1293-1[triangle], BF1291-2[triangle] (matrix); 7-219361, 18-212395 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Hanoum, Nezihé., 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 36)
        Hidjaz charki -- Mestané nigiahen -- Ouchak charki -- Mey necheh verir
        Performed by Nezihé Hanoum, vocalist
        His Master's Voice: A.X. 749; BF1913-1[triangle], BF1914-1[triangle] (matrix); 7-213877, 7-213878 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Delfino, Enrique, 1895-1967. Cup of sorrow -- Densmore, John H. (John Hopkins), 1880-1943. Cigarette, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 37)
        Performed by International Novelty Orchestra
        His Master's Voice: B1796; A27838, A28058 (matrix); 3-742 10, 3-743 9 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Canaro, Francisco, 1888-1964. Sentimento gaucho -- Donato, Edgardo. Julián, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 38)
        Performed by Varaldi Tango Band
        His Master's Voice: B 2135; Bb6872-2[triangle], Bb6854-1[triangle] (matrix); 4-226 3, 4-226 5 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Hamilton, Ord. Bow bells. You're blasé -- Sullivan, Henry, b. 1893. Bow bells. Break down and weep -- Intro: Mona Lisa, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 39)
        Performed by William Walker and Peggy Cochrane, piano duet
        His Master's Voice: B 4065; OB2548-2, OB2549-2 (matrix); 30-7939, 30-7940 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Swanstrom, Arthur, 1888-1940. Sons o' guns. Why? -- Swanstrom, Arthur, 1888-1940. Sons o' guns. It's you I love, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 40)
        Performed by Victor Arden, Phil Ohman and their Orchestra (with vocal refrain)
        His Master's Voice: B 5837; A57537-5[triangle], A57538-1[triangle] (matrix); 40-1288, 40-1289 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951. Nina Rosa. Nina Rosa -- Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951. Nina Rosa. My first love, my last love, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 41)
        His Master's Voice: B 6034; A58126-1[triangle], A58127-2[triangle] (matrix); 40-1601, 40-1639 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Alt-Wiener Tanzweisen. Liebesfreud; arr., 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 42)
        Additional title on disc: Love's joy - recorded version arr. by Rachmaninoff Additional title information: "first record," "second record"
        Performed by Sergei Rachmaninoff
        His Master's Voice: D.A. 786; A34154-3[triangle], A34155-2[triangle] (matrix); 5821, 5822 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Vivaldi, Antonio, 1678-1741. Sonatas, violin, continuo, op. 2. No. 2; arr., 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 43)
        His Master's Voice: D.A.1370; OB6050-2[square], OB6051-1[square] (matrix); 30-11741, 30-11847 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974. Saudades do Brasil. Sumaré -- Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840. Caprices, violin, M.S. 25. No. 20; arr., 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 44)
        His Master's Voice: D.A.1375; OB6053-3[square], OB6104-2[square] (matrix); 30-11742, 30-11854 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. Alt Wien. Alt Wien; arr. -- Moszkowski, Moritz, 1854-1925. Guitarre; arr., 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 45)
        His Master's Voice: D.A.1377; OB6044-2[square], OB6045-5[square] (matrix); 30-11740, 30-11353 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Musik zu Shakespeare's Viel Lärmen um nichts. Holzapfel und Schlehwein -- Elgar, Edward, 1857-1934. Capricieuse, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 46)
        His Master's Voice: D.A.1378; OB6059-2[square], OB6059-2[square] (matrix nos.); 30-11743, 30-11846 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Borel-Clerc, Charles. Tango rouge -- Sterling. Mi noche triste, 1919 November 29; 1919 December 13; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 47)
        Performed by L'Orchestre Tzigane de Monte-Carlo
        Recorded December 13 [side A], and November 29 [side B], 1919
        Disque pour Gramophone: K 702; 20931u, 20974u (matrix); 230971, 230972 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Battle. Metropole: tango argentin -- Sarrut. Sympathy: valse boston, 1919 November 10; 1919 December 1; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 48)
        Performed by L'Orchestre Symphon. du Gramophone
        Disque pour Gramophone: K 749; 20877u, 20940u (matrix); 230996, 230995 (additional matrix nos.)
        Recorded November 10 [side A], and December 1 [side B], 1919
      - Maldereu [i.e.] Malderen, E. V. Tango du rêve -- Kortlander, Max, 1890-1961. Tell me, 1920 November 12; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 49)
        Performed by l'Orchestre Symphonique du Gramophone
        Disque pour Gramophone: K 817; s21768u, s21769u (matrix); 2-230554, 2-230555 (additional matrix nos.); 4-32439 [additional matrix on side A crossed out on disc]
      - Grassi; Herpin [i.e. Harpin]. Rocking and pitching: la roula tanguette -- Hauchard, Maurice. Rêve Argentin, 1921 January 19; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 50)
        Disque pour Gramophone: K 993; s21871u, s21870u (matrix); 2-230648, 2-230649 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Padula, José L., 1893-1945. 9 de Julio -- Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951. Gigot, 1921 April 25; 1921 May 6; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 51)
        Performed by L'Orchestre Symphonique du Gramophone
        Disque pour Gramophone: K 1131; s22143u, s22101u (matrix); 2-230664, 2-230679 (additional matrix nos.)
        Recorded May 6, 1921 [side A], and April 25, 1921 [side B]
      - Toranzo, Udelino. Jueves; arr. -- Yvain, Maurice, 1891-1965. Lys noir, 1921 June 11; 1921 June 18; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 52)
        Disque pour Gramophone: K 1182; s22256u, s22241u (matrix); 2-230675, 2-230676 (additional matrix nos.)
        Recorded June 11 [side A], and June 18 [side B], 1921
      - Haines, Will E., d. 1958. Walter, Walter -- Davies, Harry Parr, 1914-1955. Trek song, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 53)
        Sung by Gracie Fields
        Liberty Music Shop: L-331; 76751A, 76752A (matrix)
      - Villa-Lobos, Heitor. Bachianas brasileiras, no. 5. Aria, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 54)
        Performed by Ruth Valdares Correa, vocal soloist; Ottetto Brasil; Villa-Lobos, conductor
        Fabrica Odeon: 104, 105 (matrix); 96, 97 (additional matrix nos.)
        "Specially recorded for New York World's Fair 1939 and the Golden Gate International Exposition"
      - Canaro, Francisco, 1888-1964. Donde hay un mango? – Discépolo, Enrique Santos, 1901-1951. Tres esperanzas, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 55)
        Performed by Francisco Canaro y su Orquesta Típica
        Odeon Disco Nacional: 4858 A/B; 7459-1, 7446 (matrix)
      - Barbosa, Orestes, 1893-1966. Sem voce – Valente, Assis, 1908-1958. Quando eu queria voce, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 56)
        Performed by Aurora Miranda, vocalist; Orchestra Odeon; Simon Beuntman, conductor
        Odeon: 11111 a/b; 4792, 4762 (matrix)
      - Atcher, Bob. You love me or you don’t: (make up your mind) – Carter, A. P. (Alvin Pleasant), 1891-1960. I’m thinking tonight of my blue eyes, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 57)
        Performed by Bob Atcher and Bonnie Blue Eyes, vocal duet with string accompaniment [side A]; Bob Atcher, vocal solo with orchestra [side B]
        Okeh: 05134; WC2738A, WC2745A (matrix)
      - Pokarekare: the ripple -- Hine e hine: slumber song, 1927; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 58)
        Performed by Ana Hato, vocalist; unidentified pianist
        Parlophone: R 3354; A-111-2, A-118-2 (matrix)
      - Hoki, hoki tonumai; Poatarau Maori: love songs – Tahi-Nei taru kino: love song; Kutia haka: war cry, 1927; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 2, Disc 59)
        Performed by Ana Hato, vocalist; unidentified chorus
        Parlophone: R 3355; A-109-3, A-113-2 (matrix)
    - Box 3: Parlophone/Pathé/Victor/Victrola/Miscellaneous Labels, 78 rpm discs
      Kreisler, Fritz; Schipa, Tito; Hato, Ana; Lamson, Carl; Waretini, Deane; Ruffo, Titta; Richardson, Albert; Gigli, Beniamino; Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943
      - Te Arawa: duet -- Matangi: love ditty, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 60)
        Performed by Ana Hato and Deane Waretini [side A], Ana Hato and chorus [side B]
        Signatures of Ana Hato and Deane Waretini etched in disc on side A
        Parlophone: R 3356; A.112, A.115
      - Hill, Alfred, 1869-1960. Waiata poi -- Te Taniwha: the dragon; Haka: war cry, 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 61)
        Performed by Ana Hato with piano accompaniment [side A], Ana Hato and chorus [side B]
        Signature of Ana Hato etched in disc on side A
        Parlophone: R 3357; A.110, A.117
      - Pibroch Donald Dhu; Bob o’ Fettercairn; Deil among the tailors -- Tulloch Macarrick; Braes o’ Tullymet; Auld wife, 1916?; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 62)
        Performed by Pipe Major Forsyth, bagpipe solo
        Pathé: 8383; 78943, 78944; 60510 (G.R etched in disc beneath number), 61542. R.A (additional numbers)
      - Hundred pipers; Miss Drummond of Perth; Sleepy Maggie -- 25th. farewell to Merut; Tulloch Gorm; Reel of Tulloch, 1916?; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 63)
        Pathé: 8431; 78945, 78946; 60247 G.R, 60708 (+, etched in disc) R.A (additional numbers)
      - Buttercup Joe: traditional -- Old sow: traditional, 1928?; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 64)
        Performed by Albert Richardson, bass, with piano [side A], Albert Richardson, bass, unaccompanied [side B]
        Regal Zonophone: T5178; X-5-42454, X-5-42455; Bb129731[triangle], Bb129741[triangle] (additional numbers etched in disc)
      - [Japanese recording], 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 65)
        Tōa-Record (Toa Phone Co., Ltd.): 321, 322 [all other information in Japanese]
      - [Japanese recording], 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 66)
        Tōa-Record (Toa Phone Co., Ltd.): 325, 326 [all other information in Japanese]
      - Mario, E. A., 1884-1961. Santa Lucia luntana (Santa Lucia, I long for you) -- Toselli, Enrico, 1883-1926. Serenade, violin, piano, op. 6; arr., 1921 April 29; 1922 September 25; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 93)
        Title from label: Serenade (Rimpianto)
        Performed by Beniamino Gigli, tenor with violin, flute, mandolin and guitar, Neopolitan [side A]; tenor with orchestra, in Italian [side B]
        Victrola: 645; H 645A 6 1, B 645B 1 1 (stamped on disc)
      - Barrera, Tomás, 1870-1938. Emigrantes. Granadinas -- Padilla, José, 1889-1960. Princesita, 1922 February 3; 1922 March 9; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 98)
        Granadinas (Farewell, my Granada) (from the Spanish operetta “Emigrantes”) -- Princesita (Little princess)
        Performed by Tito Schipa, tenor with orchestra, in Spanish
        Victrola: 827; 827A 5, 827B 10 (etched in disc)
        Recorded March 9, 1922 [side A], February 3, 1922 [side B]
      - Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci. O Colombina -- Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon. En fermant les yeux je vois, 1922 February 3; 1922 May 3; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 99)
        Pagliacci-Serenata D’Arlecchino (Harlequin’s Serenade) (Act 2) -- Manon-Il Sogno (The Dream) (Act 2)
        Performed by Tito Schipa, tenor with orchestra, in Italian
        Victrola: 828; 828A 4, 828B 17 (etched in disc)
      - Scott, Cyril, 1879-1970. Cherry ripe -- Kramer, A. Walter (Arthur Walter), 1890-1969. Entr’acte, 1922 April 25; 1923 March 30; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 100)
        Performed by Fritz Kreisler, violin solo, piano accompaniment by Carl Lamson
        Victrola: 966; 966A 4, 966B [2] (etched in disc)
      - Santa Lucia (folk song) -- Tosti, F. Paolo (Francesco Paolo), 1846-1916. Marechiare, 1923 November 27; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 101)
        (When the moon rises over Marechiare)
        Performed in Italian and in Neapolitan by Titta Ruffo, baritone; unidentified orchestra
        Victrola: 995; 995A 2, 995B 2 (etched in disc)
      - Buzzi-Peccia, Arturo, 1854-1943. Lolita -- Lerdo de Tejada, Miguel, 1869-1941. Perjura, 1922 October 13; 1923 November 27; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 103)
        Lolita (Serenade) -- Perjura (Fickle maiden!)
        Performed by Titta Ruffo, baritone; unidentified orchestra; in Italian [side A], in Spanish [side B]
        Victrola: 1019; 1019A 2, 1019B 1 (etched in disc)
        Recorded November 27, 1923 [side A], October 13, 1922 [side B]
      - Sánchez de Fuentes, Eduardo, 1874-1944. Rosalinda -- Esparza Oteo, Alfonso. Mi viejo amor (My old love), 1924 May 14; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 104)
        Performed in Spanish by Tito Schipa, tenor; unidentified orchestra
        Victrola: 1030; 1030A 2, 1030B 3 (etched in disc)
      - Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Tote Stadt. Mein Sehnen, mein Wähnen; arr. -- Bass, George. Chansonette, 1924 March 28; 1924 April 15; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 106)
        Pierrot’s dance song (from “The Dead City”) [side A]
        Performed by Fritz Kreisler, violin; Carl Lamson, piano accompaniment
        Victrola: 1062; 1062A 1, 1062B 7 (etched in disc)
      - Silvestri, Giuseppe, 1841-1921. Sérénade d’autrefois -- Barthelemy, Richard. Pesca d’ammore, 1924 May 14; 1924 September 18; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 107)
        Serenata medioevale (Serenade of olden times) -- Pesca d’ammore (Love’s angling)
        Performed in Italian, and in Neapolitan by Tito Schipa, tenor; unidentified orchestra
        Victrola: 1063; 1063A 3, 1063B 11 (etched in disc)
      - Ėĭ ukhnem; arr. -- Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Symphonies, no. 9, op. 95, E minor. Largo; arr., 1925 August 27; 1925 August 28; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 108)
        Song of the Volga boatmen: paraphrase: introducing "A Russian folk melody" -- Negro spiritual melody: adapted by Fritz Kreisler from the "Largo" of Dvořák's "New World symphony"
        Performed by Fritz Kreisler, violin; Carl Lamson, piano: violin with piano [side A], violin solo [side B]
        Victrola: 1122; 1122A 3, 1122B 14 (etched in disc)
      - Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Alt-Wiener Tanzweisen. Liebesfreud [Part 1] -- [Part 2], 1925 December 29; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 109)
        Liebesfreud-Part 1 (Love’s joy) (Old Vienna waltz) -- Liebesfreud-Part 2 (Love’s joy) (Old Vienna waltz)
        Performed by Sergei Rachmaninoff, piano solo
        Victrola: 1142; 1142A 3, 1142B 3 (etched in disc)
      - Friml, Rudolf, 1879-1972. Rose-Marie. Indian love call -- Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951. Student prince. Deep in my heart, dear, 1926; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 110)
        Performed by Fritz Kreisler, violin solo; Carl Lamson, piano
        Victrola: 1151; 1151A 7, 1151B 6 (etched in disc)
      - Friml, Rudolf, 1879-1972. Rose-Marie. Indian love call -- Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951. Student prince. Deep in my heart, dear, 1926; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 111)
        Performed by Fritz Kreisler, violin; Carl Lamson, piano
        Victor: 1151; 1151A, 1151B
      - Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948. Frasquita. Hab’ ein blaues Himmelbett; arr. -- Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948. Kreisler serenade, 1926?; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 3, Disc 112)
        Victrola: 1158; 1158A 10, 1158B 4
    - Box 4: RCA Victor/Victor/Victrola, 78 rpm discs
      City Slickers; Galli-Curci, Amelita; Achron, Isidor; Jones, Spike; Lamson, Carl; Porter, Del; Kreisler, Fritz; Benoist, André; Gluck, Alma; De Luca, Giuseppe; Caro, Julio de; Lhévinne, Josef; Sandor, Arpad; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Philadelphia Orchestra; Katz, Mickey; Caruso, Enrico; Ingle, Red; Victor Symphony Orchestra; Carlisle, Aileen; Horowitz, Vladimir; Grayson, Carl; Raucheisen, Michael; Duchin, Eddy; Hollywaiians (Musical group); Fiedler, Arthur; Boston Pops Orchestra; Vronsky, Vitya; Babin, Victor; Lhevinne, Rosina; Bay, Emanuel; Cuatro Huasos (Musical group); Barone, Clement; Herbert, Victor; Clément, Edmond; Miranda, Carmen; Reis, Mário; Bright, Sol K.; New Friends of Rhythm
      - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Stikhotvorenii︠a︡. Margaritki; arr. -- Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Morceaux, piano, op. 10. Humoresque; arr., 1926 April 8; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 113)
        Albumblatt-Marguerite (Album leaf) -- Humoresque
        Victrola: 1170; 1170A-4, 1170B-6
        Recorded April 8, 1926 [side B]
      - Nevin, Ethelbert, 1862-1901. Rosary; arr. -- Nevin, Ethelbert, 1862-1901. Mighty lak’ a rose; arr., 1928 February 7; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 114)
        Victor: 1320; 1320A-6, 1320B-2; 15937 (additional number stamped in side A)
      - Ponce, Manuel M. (Manuel María), 1882-1948. Estrellita; arr. -- Drigo, Riccardo, 1846-1930. Millions d’Arlequin. Valse bluette; arr., 1928 May 8; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 117)
        Estrellita -- Valse bluette (Air de ballet) (arr. Leopold Auer)
        Victor: 1332; 1332A-4, 1332B-5; 43945, 21068
      - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Children’s corner. Serenade for the doll -- Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757. Sonatas, harpsichord, K. 20, E major; arr., 1928 March 26, 1928 April 2; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 118)
        Sérénade à la poupée (Serenade for the doll) (no. 3 from "The children's corner") -- Capriccio
        Performed by Vladimir Horowitz, piano
        Victrola: 1353; 1353A-1, 1353B-3
      - Brandl, Johann, 1835-1913. Liebe Augustin. Du alter Stefansturm; arr. -- Heuberger, Richard, 1850-1914. Opernball. Im chambre séparée; arr., 1930?; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 119)
        Old refrain (Viennese popular song) -- Opera ball: Midnight bells
        Performed by Fritz Kreisler, violin; Michael Raucheisen, piano
        Victor: 1465; 1465A-3, 1465B-3; BLR 6061-3[triangle], BLR 6066-3[triangle]
        Recorded in Europe
      - Di Capua, Eduardo, 1864-1917. O sole mio -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto. Donna è mobile, 1933; Disc is missing a small chip; beginning of recording on side B may be affected; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 120)
        Performed by Enrico Caruso, tenor; Victor Symphony Orchestra
        Victor: 1616; 1616A-1, 1616B-1
      - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. Songs from Shakespeare’s plays. Arise; arr. -- Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Skazka o t︠s︡are Saltane. Nu, teperʹ, moĭ shmelʹ -- Godowsky, Leopold, 1870-1938. Triakontameron. Alt Wien; arr., 1934; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 123)
        1. Sea murmurs 2. Bumble bee -- Alt Wien (Old Vienna)
        Victor: 1645; 1645A-2, 1645B-2
      - Lyadov, Anatoly Konstantinovich, 1855-1914. Russkie narodnye pesni, orchestra. Selections, 1934 March 17; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 124)
        Eight Russian folk dances (Liadow): [side A:] No. 5-Legend of the birds -- No. 6-Cradle song -- [side B:] No. 7-Round dance -- No. 8-Village dance song
        Performed by the Philadelphia Orchestra; Leopold Stokowski, conductor
        Victor: 1681; 1681A-1, 1681B-1
      - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Enfant prodigue. Prélude; arr. -- Moszkowski, Moritz, 1854-1925. Guitarre; arr., 1935; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 125)
        L’enfant prodigue: prelude (Debussy) -- Guitarre (Moszkowski, Op. 45, No. 2-arr. Sarasate)
        Victor: 1694; 1694A-2, 1694B-5; OB 6055-2[square], OB 6045-5[square]
      - Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840. Caprices, violin, M.S. 25. No. 20; arr. -- Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840. Caprices, violin, M.S. 25. No. 13; arr., 1934; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 126)
        Caprice, Op. 1, No. 20 (Paganini-Kreisler) -- Caprice, Op. 1, No. 13 (Paganini-Kreisler)
        Victor: 1697; 1697A-2, 1697B-2; OB 6104-2[square], OB 6105[square]2
      - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Nocturnes, orchestra. Fêtes; arr., 1935 June 11; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 127)
        Fêtes-part 1 (Festivals) (Debussy-Ravel) -- Fêtes-part 2 (Festivals)
        Performed by Josef & Rosina Lhevinne, piano duo
        Victor: 1741; 1741A, 1741B
      - Vivaldi, Antonio, 1678-1741. Sonatas, violin, continuo, op. 2. No. 2; arr., 1934 February 21; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 128)
        Suite in A Major-part 1: Preludio and capriccio (Vivaldi-arr. Busch) -- Suite in A Major-concluded: Corrente -- recitativo -- giga
        Victor: 1810; 1810A-2, 1810B-1; OB 6050-2[square], OB 6051-1[square]
      - Dinicu, Grigoraș. Hora staccato; arr. -- Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Musik zu Shakespeare’s Viel Lärmen um nichts. Holzapfel und Schlehwein, 193-?; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 131)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Emanuel Bay, piano [side A], Arpad Sander, piano [side B]
        Victor: 1864; 1864A-1, 1864B-2; OEA 4894-1[square], OB 6054-2[square]
      - Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Skazka o t︠s︡are Saltane. Nu, teperʹ, moĭ shmelʹ; arr. -- Babin, Victor, 1908-1972. Etudes, pianos (2) no. 1, 1937 March 9; Disc is missing a small chip on side B that affects beginning of recording; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 132)
        Flight of the bumblebee (from opera “The fairy tale of Tsar Saltan”) (Act 3) (Rimsky-Korsakow - Babin) -- Etude No. 1 (Babin)
        Performed by Vitya Vronsky and Victor Babin, piano duo
        Victor: 4377; 4377A-1, 4377B-3
      - McBride, Robert, 1911-2007. Fugato on a well-known theme -- Mosolov, A. (Aleksandr), 1900-1973. Stalʹ. Zavod, 1938; 10" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 4, Disc 133)
        [Side B:] Soviet iron foundry (A. Mossolow)
        Performed by Boston “Pops” Orchestra; Arthur Fiedler, conductor
        Victor: 4378, 4378A-1, 4378B-1